# Dr. Chuanxia Zheng

## Research Interests

His research interests focus on computer vision and machine learning, especially for creative AI. He has done a wide range of work on 2D and 3D scene synthesis, with the goal of synthesizing a photorealistic physical world via generative AI. In particular, on topics:

- 3D and 4D reconstruction from images or videos.
- 3D editing via object-centric perception.
- Generative models for physical world perception and reasoning.
- Multi-modalities (1D, 2D, 3D, and 4D) generation and understanding.

# Professional experience

- 2024 Marie Skłodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA) Fellow, University of Oxford, UK. 3D scene creation from images or videos
- 2022–24 Postdoctoral Research Fellow, University of Oxford, UK.

2D and 3D scene synthesis

2021–22 Research Fellow, Monash University, Australia.

Codebook learning for 2D and 3D synthesis

### Education

### 2017–21 Doctor of Philosophy (PhD).

Nanyang Technological University

School of Computer Science and Engineering, Singapore

Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning Outstanding PhD Thesis Award, Advisors: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai

2014–17 Master of Science (MSc) in computer science.

Beihang University, Beijing, China

Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot

Advisors: Jianhua Wang and Weihai Chen

## 2010–14 Bachelor of Science in information engineering.

Beijing Jiaotong University, Beijing, China

Thesis: Image Retrieval based on Visual Saliency

Highest Honours (Outstanding Graduate of Beijing), Advisor: Ze Liu

## Research Experience

2022- Research Fellow, University of Oxford, UK, Prof. Andrea Vedaldi.

Research interests: 3D reconstruction from limited images or videos

2021-22 Research Fellow, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai.

Research interests: nature scene generation and completion

2017-21 PhD, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann.

Research interests: photorealistic image generation

# Grants

- 2024- €236,748, PI, "Synthesizing Photorealistic 3D Scene", HORIZON-MSCA, EP/Z001811/1
- 2024- €5,910, Co-PI, "Object-Centric 3D Reconstruction and Decomposition", Bayarian Funding.

# Awards and other recognitions

- 2024 DAAD Ainet Fellowship
- 2024 HORIZON Marie Skłodowska-Curie (HORIZON-MSCA) Fellowship
- 2023 Outstanding Reviewer Award, CVPR
- 2022 Scholar/Travel Award, NeurIPS
- 2022 Outstanding PhD Thesis Award, NTU, Singapore
- 2021 Outstanding Reviewer Award, IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM)
- 2017 NTU Research Scholarship
- 2014 Outstanding Graduate of Beijing
- 2012 Hanergy Scholarship Award (**Top 1%**)
- 2011 Siemens Scholarship Award (**Top 1%**)

# Press Coverage

- 2024 Hacker News: Zero-Shot Gaussian Splatting from Uncalibrated Image Pairs
- 2024 Hacker News: MVSplat: Efficient 3D Gaussian Splatting from Sparse Multi-View Images
- 2023 Sber.ru: MoVQ 0.1 means a lot for text-image generation Kandinsky 2.1 (Github: 2.7K)
- 2022 Phys.org: Researchers unravel cell biology through artificial intelligence
- 2022 NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022
- 2022 Zhuanzhi: How to create photorealistic images? Ph.D. Thesis by Dr. Zheng
- 2021 kknews, Sohu, NetEase: AgileGAN a tool for creating stylized portraits (Demo: 10K/week)

# Service to the academic community

- Area Chair. ACM Multimedia 2024, BMVC 2024.
- Reviewer for international journals. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (**TPAMI**), International Journal on Computer Vision (**IJCV**), IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (**TIP**), IEEE Transactions on Multimedia(**TMM**), Computer Vision and Image Understanding (**CVIU**), The Visual Computer (**TVC**).
- Reviewer for international conferences. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2020-2024, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2020, 2022, 2024, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019, 2021, 2023, International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2022-2024, International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021-2024, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2023, International Conference on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH) 2021,2022, International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2023.

## International workshops

2024 "Second Workshop for Learning 3D with Multi-View Supervision" at the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) with Abdullah Hamdi, Silvio Giancola, Guocheng Qian, Jinjie Mai, Sara Rojas Martinez, Bernard S. Ghanem, and Yash Bhalgat.

# Mentoring and student supervision

#### PhD

- 2024- Zeren Jiang, Oxford, co-supervised with Prof. Andrea Vedaldi and Dr. Iro Laina
- 2023- Brandon Smart, Oxford, co-supervised with Prof. Victor Prisacariu and Dr. Iro Laina
- 2023- Ruining Li, Oxford, co-supervised with Prof. Andrea Vedaldi and Christian Rupprecht
- 2023- Tianhao Wu, NTU, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham

- 2022-23 Minghui Hu, NTU, three terms with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham
- 2021-24 Yuedong Chen, Monash University, co-supervised with Prof. Jianfei Cai

#### Master

- 2024- Wenbo Ji, TUM, co-supervised with Dr. Yan Xia and Prof. Daniel Cremers
- 2024-24 Filip Skubacz, TUM, co-supervised with Dr. Yan Xia and Prof. Daniel Cremers
- 2024-24 Nina Kirakosyan, TUM, co-supervised with Dr. Yan Xia and Prof. Daniel Cremers
- 2024-24 Michael Neumayr, TUM, co-supervised with Dr. Yan Xia and Prof. Daniel Cremers

## Teaching

- 2023-24 **Teaching Assistant**, B16: Software Engineering, Undergraduate, University of Oxford.
- 2023-23 **Teaching**, Generative AI, Graduate, University of Oxford.
- 2018–20 Teaching Assistant, Advanced Digital Image Processing, Graduate, NTU.
- 2018–20 Teaching Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction, Undergraduate, NTU.
- 2018–19 Teaching Assistant, Engineering Mathematics, Undergraduate, NTU.

## Invited talks

- 2024 Physi4D: Physically interactive 4D natural world creation, NTU, Singapore, NTU.
- 2023 Visiting the Invisible via Generative AI, University of Science and Technology, China.
- 2023 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Harbin Institute of Technology, China.
- 2023 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, NTU, Singapore.
- 2023 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, University of Oxford, UK.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, NTU, Singapore, Link.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, University of Oxford, UK.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, ETH, Zürich.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, University of Science and Technology, China.
- 2019 Pluralistic Image Completion, NTU, Singapore.
- 2018 Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore.

## **Publications**

- [32] Stanislaw Szymanowicz, Eldar Insafutdinov, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Dylan Campbell, Jao Henriques, Christian Rupprecht, and Andrea Vedaldi. Flash3d: Feed-forward generalisable scene reconstruction from a single image. In *3DV*, 2024. URL: https://www.robots.ox.ac.uk/vgg/research/flash3d/.
- [31] Yuedong Chen, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Haofei Xu, Bohan Zhuang, Andrea Vedaldi, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Mvsplat360: Benchmarking 360-degree generalizable 3d novel view synthesis from sparse views. In *NeurIPS*, 2024. URL: https://donydchen.github.io/mvsplat360/.
- [30] Guanqi Zhan, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weidi Xie, and Andrew Zisserman. A general protocol to probe large vision models for 3d physical understanding. In *NeurIPS*, 2024.
- [29] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Bohan Zhuang, Marc Pollefeys, Andreas Geiger, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Mysplat: Efficient 3d gaussian splatting from sparse multi-view images. In *ECCV*, 2024. URL: https://donydchen.github.io/mysplat/.
- [28] Ruining Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Christian Rupprecht, and Andrea Vedaldi. Dragapart: Learning a part-level motion prior for articulated objects. In *ECCV*, 2024. URL: https://dragapart.github.io/.
- [27] Tianhao Wu, Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Qianyi Wu. Clusteringsdf: Self-organized

- neural implicit surfaces for 3d decomposition. In ECCV, 2024. URL: https://sm0kywu.github-.io/ClusteringSDF/.
- [26] Chuanxia Zheng, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity pluralistic image completion. TPAMI, 2024. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/picformer/.
- [25] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Free3d: Consistent novel view synthesis without 3d representation. In *CVPR*, 2024. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/free3d/.
- [24] Guanqi Zhan, Chuanxia Zheng, Weidi Xie, and Andrew Zisserman. Amodal ground truth and completion in the wild. In *CVPR*, 2024. URL: https://www.robots.ox.ac.uk/vgg/research/.
- [23] Minghui Hu, Jianbin Zheng, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Tat-Jen Cham. One more step: A versatile plug-and-play module for rectifying diffusion schedule flaws and enhancing low-frequency controls. In *CVPR*, 2024. URL: https://jabirzheng.github.io/OneMoreStep/.
- [22] Tianhao Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Panodiffusion: 360-degree panorama outpainting via diffusion. In *ICLR*, 2024. URL: https://sm0kywu.github.io/panodiffusion/.
- [21] Minghui Hu, Jianbin Zheng, Daqing Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Tat-Jen Cham. Cocktail: Mixing multi-modality control for text-conditional image generation. In *NeurIPS*, 2023. URL: https://mhh0318.github.io/cocktail/.
- [20] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Online clustered codebook. In ICCV, 2023. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/cvq/.
- [19] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Vector quantized wasserstein auto-encoder. In *ICML*, 2023.
- [18] Minghui Hu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Heliang Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Zuopeng Yang, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Ponnuthurai N. Suganthan. Unified discrete diffusion for simultaneous vision-language generation. In *ICLR*, 2023. URL: https://mhh0318.github.io/unid3/.
- [17] Chuanxia Zheng, Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. In *NeurIPS*, 2022. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com.
- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan\*, Chuanxia Zheng\*, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, Chuanxia Zheng, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In ECCV, 2022. URL: <a href="https://wuqianyi.top/objectsdf/">https://wuqianyi.top/objectsdf/</a>.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In *ECCV*, 2022. URL: https://donydchen.github.io/sem2nerf/.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In *CVPR*, pages 11512–11522, June 2022. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/tfill/.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021. URL: <a href="https://chuanxiaz.com/vinv/">https://chuanxiaz.com/vinv/</a>.

- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, Chuanxia Zheng, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *ICCV*, pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(10):2786–2805, 2021. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/pic/.
- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. *ACM Transactions on Graphics* (*TOG*), 40(4):1–13, 2021. URL: https://guoxiansong.github.io.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In *CVPR*, 2021. URL:https://chuanxiaz.com/flsesim/.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *CVPR*, pages 1438–1447, 2019. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/pic/.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In *VCIP*, pages 1–4, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In *ECCV*, pages 767–783, 2018. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/synthetic2real/.
- [4] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *TVCJ*, 34(5):735–747, 2018.
- [3] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. *TVCJ*, 33(12):1587–1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In *ROBIO*. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In *ICIEA*, pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

## Preprint

- [3] Brandon Smart, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Iro Laina, and Victor Adrian Prisacariu. Splatt3r: Zero-shot gaussian splatting from uncalibrated image pairs. *Under reviewer*, 2024.
- [2] LongTung Vuong, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Manh Luong, Thanh-Toan Do, Dinh Phung, and Trung Le. Kefi: Kernel-based feature identification for generalizable classification. *Under reviewer*.
- [1] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Explicit correspondence matching for generalizable neural radiance fields. *Under reviewer*.